

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







Lead Consultant/Principal Consultant seeking roles in Software
Development, Application Programming, Requirement Gathering, Client
Management, Program Management, SQL Server, .NET, C#, PLSQL, DevOps



Total Experience: 15 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: MCA[Computers]

 $\hbox{\it Current Designation: Lead Consultant/Principal Consultant}$ 

Current Company: Infosys Limited

Current Location: Pune

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Mumbai, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance
Role: Tech Architect

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Lead Consultant/Principal Consultant, Tech Architect, Software Development, Application

Program Management, SQL Server, NET, C#,PLSQL, DevOps

Verified : Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 23-Jan-21 Last Modified: 23-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education |

## Summary

Technical and Functional Leader with 15+ years of success in heading large transformation projects with cutting edge Blue Yonder solutions across Retail & Supply Chain domains; 8 years of international experience in Chicago

Innate capabilities in mapping business problems, driving automations and developing state-of-the-art JDA solutions based on Floor Planning, Space Planning & Automations, Assortment Optimization, Category Knowledge Base and Open Access, BY Luminate Control Tower

Skilled program manager having experience of handling multiple transformation and implementation programs with additional responsibilities of appraisals and hiring

Technical Expert in Mcrosoft C#.NET, SQL Server, Oracle, SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS), BY Space Automation Pro

# **Work Experience**

Infosys Limited as Lead Consultant/Principal Consultant Jul 2017 to Till Date

Growth Path:

Lead Consultant/Principal Consultant July 2017 - Present

#### Key Deliverables:

Collaborated with cross-functional business and IT teams to design & deliver critical solutions across the retail domain; provided strategic level operational support to end users in various JDA Applications

Designed JDA solutions in alignment with business requirements; mapped opportunities & steered application improvements; implemented best practices & driven key process enhancements

Defined solution architecture for and end to end solution considering key business functions and performance parameters

Implemented BY Category Management Solutions along with Space Automation Pro customizations and automations

Lead design and development of downstream and upstream processes and technical data flows Spearheaded projects from planning to execution; implemented project plans within preset budgets; performed key tasks including design, specification/configuration, test and product integrations within various environments

Managed bidding for new opportunities; prepared proposals, delivered business presentations to clients, optimized resources, estimated efforts & managed risks; submitted RFP responses for proposals across NA/EU/APAC regions for various JDA specific opportunities

Interfaced with Category Management teams across supermarket chains, food retailers, cards and gift retailers and wholesalers for creating & maintaining planogram, floor plan and assortment range prototypes Automated business processes and provided high level inputs based on JDA Space Planning, Floor Planning and Assortment solutions; resolved integration issues with focus on optimizing performance and scalability Highlights:

Successfully led 5 RFP response(s) for the retail clients valued at USD 15 million till date
Successful implementation of BY Category Management 2017.2 on 9 different geographies for a global
supermarket chain Successfully extended the canabilities of Blue Yonder Category Management using automation

# 1

# **Important**

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld. supermanet enum successium exemice une cupulmuse en bue remoi succysty management using automater

techniques and

customized solutions for a major US wholesale business

Successfully roll out store-corporate communication platform and product sequencing for a leading food

Awards & Recognitions:

o Walmart Glory Award

o Infosys ACE (Always Creating Excellence) award

Project (Value) Contributions:

Retail Transformation Program for a major Gift & Card Retailer in US

Explore and confirm customer challenges and redefined the business processes to meet market best practices

Functional and technical design for Reports, interfaces, Conversions, Enhancements, Forms and workflows

Leading business process transformation and aligning with business processes

Implementation of Blue Yonder Category Management 2019.2 modules e.g. Assortment Optimization, Space Planning, Floor Planning and Web Publisher (Open Access)

Blue Yonder Category Management Extension of a major food retailer in US

Major functionality enhancement to ensure seamless communication between corporate and store users for published planograms and floorplans

Performance improvement on out of the box batch solutions by redesigning functionalities

Designed one portal to maintain product, planograms and floorplans with extended functionalities

Integrated Assortment and Space planning and automated planogram creation based on assortment recommendations

Blue Yonder Category Management 2017.2 Implementation for 9 international markets for a global supermarket chain

Streamlining of upstream and downstream data flows by using latest technologies

Solution architecture design for end to end implementation of JDA Category Management implementation and data feeds

Led overall project development and rollout for 9 geographies including US, UK, Canada, China, Mexico, Chile, Brazil, Argentina

Overall batch job time reduced from 8-10 hours to 1-2 hours and productivity increased by 25-30%

#### Tata Consultancy Services as Blue Yonder Techno-functional consultant Feb 2005 to Jun 2017

Key Deliverables

Managed the JDA CKB Implementation and Upgrade project focused towards optimizing space planning activities by implementing space automation Pro tool; integrated macro space planning system with CAD operation & drawings

Managed a major Retail Transformation Program and integrated SAP modules with JDA Category Management suite of applications

Enabled Promotional Planogram creations and automatic placement based on fixture rankings, performance and space availability to achieve targeted communication to stores and accurate promotional space utilization Enabled seasonal planogram creation and automatic placements by utilizing category adjacencies and placement rules for each store cluster

Overall program management

Headed all critical phases of projects that includes formulating project plans, requirement gathering, design, implementation, configuration, documentation, resource allocation & execution

^ Back to Top

## **Education**

UG: B.Sc (Maths) from university of rajasthan, jaipur in 2000

PG: MCA (Computers) from University of Rajasthan, Jaipur in 2004

^ Back to Top

### **Affirmative Action**

### **Work Authorization**

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.